以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
低阶矩阵如此重要的功能
low rank matrices so important function
矩阵他们可以真正低等级
matrices they can be truly low rank like
紫外线转置是排名第一和我们
UV transpose that's a rank one and we
对那些问题有一些疑问
have some questions about those and then
本章后面将讨论矩阵
later in the chapter will meet matrices
虽然排名在哪里
that are approximately though rank where
奇异值就像下降一样
the the singular values drop off like
疯了，那些非常了不起
crazy and those are quite remarkable
矩阵确定，这是我的话题
matrices ok so that this is my topic at
一开始，如果不采取
the beginning and it if it doesn't take
整整一个小时我想回去
the whole hour I want to go back to a
第2章第2章中的主题
topic in in chapter chapter 2 that
应该是2.4，我们是最后一次
should be 2.4 where we were last time
好的，所以这是在一小时后期
good ok so that's for late in the hour
这是现在所以我希望它让我们专注
this is for now so I want it let's focus
对此我有什么问题
on this so what's the question there I
从身份矩阵Iperturb开始
start with the identity matrix I perturb
它通过排名1的矩阵，我问什么
it by a matrix of rank 1 and I ask what
反之亦然，我正在做一个小事
the inverse is so I'm making a small
当我说小时改变矩阵
change in the matrix when I say small
改变我不是说数字是
change I don't mean that the numbers are
事实上，你知道它可以紫外线
small in fact you know it could UV
转置可能是所有的女主人
transpose could be the all ones matron
或者所有的数百万甚至矩阵，但它
or all Millions matrix even but it's
等级很小就是那个
rank is small that's what's that's the
小这种想法是很重要的位置，并
idea of small that's important here and
我想知道反面是什么
I would like to know what the inverse is
这就是4.1和4.1中的问题
so that's the question here in 4.1 and
有一个着名的公式，有
there's a famous formula that has at
至少三个名字，可能更多和
least three names and probably more and
它也被称为矩阵求逆
it's also called the matrix inversion
信号处理中的公式让我
formula in signal processing and let me
记下这个例子，所以我开始吧
write down the example so here I start
使用单位矩阵我排名1
with the identity matrix I do a rank 1
扰动，我想知道是什么
perturbation and I want to know what's
反过来，我会写下来的
the inverse and I'll write down the
回答并检查它是否是正确的那么
answer and check that it's correct so
我正在扰乱身份矩阵
i'm perturbing the identity matrix in
这种情况的逆也是
this case whose inverse is also the
单位矩阵所以我要写
identity matrix so I'm going to write
作为一种排列的答案
the answer as a as a permutation as a
我和这个问题的扰动是
perturbation of I and the question is
什么是扰动，它是一个
what is that perturbation and it's a
着名的配方有一个UV转置
famous formula there's a UV transpose
从那里复制除以1
comes in copied from there divided by 1
减去vtransposeu现在让我们先来
minus v transpose u now let's first of
所有这些只是看到这些是一个
all just see that these are this is a
合理的配方，所以使用列U和
reasonable formula so use a column U and
V是列向量，因为UV总是如此
V are column vectors as always so UV
transpose是一列矩阵列
transpose is a matrix column times row
所以我从中减去了
so I it's being subtracted from the
身份和这边我在这边
identity and over here on this side I
将UV转置再次排名第一
have UV transpose again a rank one
矩阵除以数字，这就是
matrix divided by a number so that's the
指出这是一个数字
point this is a number
一个接一个矩阵，你可以这样说
a one by one matrix you could say so the
这个公式的要点就是找到了
point of this formula is to find the
N乘n矩阵的逆
inverse of an N by n matrix in terms of
1乘1矩阵的逆矩阵
the inverse of a 1 by 1 matrix which is
我的意思是更简单，更容易做到
a lot simpler and easier to do I mean
右手边显然很容易
that right hand side is clearly easy and
让我们看看它告诉我们的其他事情
let's see what other things it tells us
所以这是一个秩1扰动
so this was a Rank 1 perturbation in the
身份然后，当我反转，我得看看
identity then when I invert I get look
在此这也是1级，这是一个
at this this is also a rank 1 that's a
这其实数量是非常相同的
number that's in fact it's the very same
等级1，我们在这个有没有在这
rank 1 that we had there in this in this
好的情况如此结论，如果我改变你的
nice case so conclusion if I change your
矩阵按等级1改变它的倒数
matrix by rank 1 I change its inverse by
排名第一，似乎并不完全
rank one that doesn't seem completely
很明显，直到你弄明白
obvious until you go to figure it out
当你搞清楚时，你会得到一个公式
when you figure it out you get a formula
到目前为止，我告诉你的是我
that tells you well so far what I'm
扰动是我的身份矩阵
perturbing is the identity matrix when I
到达这里我会扰乱任何矩阵
get here I'm gonna perturb any matrix
如果，我会得出同样的结论
I'm gonna reach the same conclusion if
这是排名1然后是变化
this is rank 1 then the change in the
逆也是排名1，但让我们看看它
inverse is also rank 1 but let's see it
第一个平等的身份，所以我
first for a equal the identity so I
我猜我有两三个问题
guess I have two or three questions one
将如何检查这是什么
would be how do you check that this is
再次纠正，记住它在做什么
correct again remember what it's doing
它的漂亮整洁是它的计算
it's pretty neat it's it's computing an
N乘以1乘以1乘以1
N by n inverse in terms of a 1 by 1
反过来我只是一个数字而且那就是
inverse I just it's a number and that's
这肯定是一个有利的交流所以它是
a certainly a favorable exchange so it's
你想要的公式和a
a formula that you want and and a
这个公式非常有用
formula that's quite useful
是的，让我看看公式
yeah let me just check the formula
在我谈论它如何有用之前
before I talk about how how it's useful
所以如何检查它我猜是否这样
so how shall I check it I guess if this
声称是逆，然后让我们
is claimed to be the inverse then let's
只是检查所以这将是检查
just check so this will be the check
我将乘以我加上UV
I'll multiply by by that I plus UV
转换一个减去V转置你
transpose over one minus V transpose you
声称的反转和我希望的是什么
the claimed inverse and what am i hoping
从这个乘法得到我，我
to get from this multiplication I I'm
想知道我希望那个结果是
wondering I'm hoping that that result is
身份矩阵所以我要去
the identity matrix so I'm just going to
做到这一点我们会看到身份
do it out and we'll see the identity
出现让我这么快就让我这么做
appear so that times I so let me just
先写下那部分我减去紫外线
write that part first I minus UV
转置，现在我减去UV转置
transpose and now I minus UV transpose
这是为了减去紫外线
times this so that's I minus UV
转置xUV转置超过一个减号
transpose x UV transpose over one minus
V转置你就是这样
V transpose u that's it's just just
将它乘以看到我们
multiplying it out and seeing that we
得到身份好吧我看到了身份
get the identity okay I see the identity
所以我想我希望这一切
there so I guess I hope that all this
这部分减少到它减少了什么
this part reduces to what does it reduce
好吧，让我在那里做那个分子
to okay let me do that numerator there
所以这是UV转置减去upoo减去
so that's UV transpose minus u poo minus
u次V转置你看到了什么
u times V transpose u do you see what's
发生在这里V转置关键是
happening here V transpose the key is
当我乘以那个倍数时
that when I multiplied that times that
我连续做了四件事，而且我做了
I've got four things in a row and I do
中间对首先因为那是一个
the middle pair first because that's a
数字V转置你所以我有紫外线
number V transpose u so I had UV
转移从那
transpose from that
和UV转置次数-数量
and UV transpose times that number - do
你知道我在这里得到了什么
you see what have I got here I've got
我已经知道了，我现在已经进行了紫外线转换
I've got ya I've got UV transpose I now
我将1-v转置因子分解出来
i factor out a 1 - v transpose u which
正是我想要的这是一个因素
is just what I want this is a factor
然后1减V将你移出这里
then 1 minus V transpose u out of here
它取消了那些然后我就是
it's there cancel those and then I'm
留下一个取消的UV转置
left with a UV transpose which cancels
那并留下了它的亲切身份
that and leaves the identity it's kind
魔术当然是有人拥有的
of magic of course it was somebody had
在第一个中找出那个公式
to figure out that formula in the first
地方我可以，我可以做下一个，如果
place I could I could do the next one if
你喜欢，因为我在滚动
you like since I'm on a roll
假设我现在采取第二个是什么
suppose I take the second one now what's
它的紫外转置的差异，但
the difference in its UV transpose but
那些较大字母在U和V
those are larger letters the U and the V
那么如果我的意思是那些呢？
so what if one of my meaning by those
那些是矩阵，是的，这是一个更大的
those are matrices yeah this is a bigger
等级U是U是有K列V.
rank U is a U is a has K columns V
转置有K行他们产品
transpose has K rows they that product
UV转置是KbyK所以让我看看
UV transpose is K by K so let me see
我认为这个公式现在会如此
what I think the formula would be so now
我减去UV转置，所以这是
I minus UV transpose inverse so this is
n乘以K乘以K乘以n得到n乘以n
n by K times K by n so it's n by n
矩阵，这是想法的身份
matrix and this is the idea identities
但它的等级是什么等级
but it's rank is what is the rank of
现在好了正确的，所以我在这里
that now okay right so I have here the
整件事就是整件事
whole thing is the whole thing is the
N乘n矩阵的逆，所以我有一个
inverse of an N by n matrix so I have an
Nbynmatrix让我把它放在这里n
N by n matrix let me put that up here n
通过n矩阵反转
by n matrix to invert
还有它是好的，我会写下来
there it is okay I'm gonna write down
你能够达到的公式
the formula you're gonna be able to
写下来，因为它只是复制
write it down because it's just copy
从那个复制，你会看到
copied from that one and you'll see that
它涉及KbyKinverse，所以我有
it involves a K by K inverse so I have
N×n矩阵反转，但我没有
an N by n matrix to invert but I don't
必须这样做我可以把它切换到K.
have to do that I can switch it to a K
通过K矩阵，这很漂亮没关系
by K matrix that's like pretty nice okay
所以我们这样做吧
so so let's do it
所以我基本上要复制我加
so I'm basically gonna copy that I plus
你现在我是矩阵所以我就是这样的
you now I'm matrices so I I so that's an
逆，但我不能把它作为一个
inverse but I can't leave it as a
分母，因为我们在这里
denominator because we're here we're
谈到由K矩阵AK，这是
talking about a K by K matrix this is
现在这很好，所以我必须这样做
this is now this is well so I have to
把它像任何矩阵逆IK减去
put it like any matrix inverse I K minus
V转置你反转所以我只是
V transpose u inverse so I'm just
明智地复制这个公式
copying this formula wisely taking the
你首先要比这个部分好
you first than this part and then
最后V转置我把这个
finally the V transpose I put this one
这一个现在已经成功了
up this one now has made that one
过时的右这是字母k等于
obsolete right this was the case k equal
一个在这里，但我认为它有助于
one over here but I think it helps to
看到这肯定有助于我看到
see it this certainly helps me to see
公式首先排名第一
the formula first for a rank one
扰动，非常非常
perturbation which is pretty much a very
可能的可能性，然后看到我们
likely possibility and then see that we
有我完全类似的公式应
have I totally analogous formula shall
我们这有点乐趣，以检查它，所以我
we it's sort of fun to check it so I
打算做同样的检查，但我会
plan to do the same check but but I'll
请注意，我有一个KbyK所以
just notice here that I have a K by K so
我正在交换一些东西
I'm exchanging something that's a
n的身份和n的扰动
perturbation of I of n by n identity and
n由n矩阵表示必须反转
n by n matrix for to have to invert
什么是KbyK矩阵
something that's a K by K matrix
K的身份很多地扰乱了K.
perturbing the K by K identity much
在这种情况下，较小的是k就是一个
smaller in that case k was one so are
你现在好好检查它，所以我想要
you good for checking it now so I want
通过这个和多个多重我
to multiple multiple I that by this and
希望得到我是这个身份
hopefully get I am the identity this is
最后，我不是，我应该
the end by in I didn't yeah I should I
没有给予这两个或三个奖励
haven't given credit to the two or three
或者可能有11个人找到了
or four possibly 11 people who found
这个公式，我不明白哦，是的
this formula and I not see oh yeah here
是他们的名字
are their names
是不是好让他们通过著名
is it okay to make them famous by
把他们的名字放在这里是谢尔曼
putting their names up here yes Sherman
我无法告诉你是谁做了什么的
and I couldn't tell you who did what
莫里森伍德伯里
Morrison Woodbury
然后也许没人会怀疑别人
and then nobody doubt others right maybe
其中一人做了一个这样做排名
one of them did that one did this rank
一个案例，然后另一个案例
one case and then another generalized it
然后你可以从中看到
and then you could see from that from
那里的大纲最终我们会
the outline there that eventually we'll
我们当然可以扰乱矩阵
we can perturb a matrix a of course
那不会比那更难
that's not gonna be much harder than the
身份好吧让我们做一个
identity okay let's let's do just one
更多检查，然后显示它是如何
more check and then show how it could be
使用好吧好吧我乘以那个
used okay okay I multiply that by that
我们可以做到这这件事倍
can we do that this this thing times
这个并希望得到这样的身份
this and hope to get the identity so
首先，我会写下这件事
first I'll write down this thing there's
我不会平等的东西，因为我
something I won't put equal because I'm
不是我乘以那就好了
not I'm multiplying that by that okay so
我通过n减去UV转置
I get by n minus UV transpose on the
左边当然我得到了
left side of course I'm getting the
身份，我希望希望我得到
identity and I hope hoping I'm getting
在右边的身份所以我
the identity on the right so I'm
这个相乘我做到了，现在有我
multiplying by this I did it there now I
必须把我减去UV转置它
have to put I minus UV transpose it
在这里面对你我是负V
takes face here you I'm minus V
转置u逆V转置gulp所以
transpose u inverse V transpose gulp so
我只是留在那里，或者你就是你
I just leave it there or you're you're
午餐时你很坚强让我们看看我们是什么
at lunch you're strong let's see what we
可以做到还好这部分罚款好吧，这
can do okay this part fine okay this
部分哦，男孩我在这里做什么诀窍
part oh boy what do I do here the trick
是要成为这个不要看
is gonna be that this don't be looking
它可以写的东西
thing there it can be written
不同的是，让我们告诉我什么
differently well let's just tell me what
等于它等于你减去紫外线
it equals it equals u minus u v
颠倒
transpose
你写的每个人都看到了，但现在
you write everybody sees that but now
我要做什么我要把它放进去
what am I gonna do I'm gonna put the
括号不同
parentheses differently
我带来了你，你这是在
I'm bringing the you the you that was on
在那里，我会穿上它
the right up there I'm gonna put it on
左边你看到的就是这样
the left you see that so so this is
显然你减去UV转移你和
obviously you minus UV transpose you and
现在我要把另一个放在右边
now I'm going to put right at another
时间是你的时间我减去V转置
time it's you times I minus V transpose
你，我会把你从中分解出来
you I'm gonna factor that you out of on
左侧而不是它的位置
the left side instead of where it
最初来自右侧
originally came on the right side of
这没关系你怎么看好消息
this okay you see how see the great news
是的，这实际上是好的
there yeah this was actually well
由你的教授偶然组织
organized by your professor by accident
好吧那我现在该做什么呢
okay so what do I do now this thing look
我到底就是我所拥有的
I've got exactly here what I've got
完全倒在那里，我有我
inverted there so altogether I have I
减去UV转置加上你这个
minus UV transpose Plus this you this
取消时间V转置所以我得到了我
cancelled times V transpose so I get I
所以这只是这个小花招
so it was just this little sleight of
你右手进来的地方
hand where you came in on the right and
在左边出来没关系，是一个
came out on the left okay and be a
现在有类似的公式
similar formula with a in there so now
这是一个公平的问题，是怎么做的
it's a fair question how did anybody
想出这些公式，我们就是这样
come up with these formulas we're we're
通过检查证明它们是正确的
proving them correct just by checking
他们认同他们的身份
that they that they give the identity
矩阵我们应该如何思考
matrix we should really think how that
如何在第一个中找到公式
how to find the formula in the first
我可以回到这个地方怎么样
place I could go back to this one how
你能在第一个中找到那个公式吗？
could you find that formula in the first
放置好这里是应该做的一种方式
place well here's one way to do it
-所以-这是一个即将发现的
- so - - this is an about to discover
然后我在这里让我放过
and then I over here let me put over
我想到这里使用这个公式
here to use the formula while I think of
它实际上我有两个用于
it and actually I have two to uses in
心灵使用一个就是解决所以我只是
mind use one would be to solve so I just
做我想我想要这样这是我的
doing I suppose I want to so this is my
新矩阵UV转置x等于一些
new matrix UV transpose x equals some
右手边B解决了一个线性系统
right hand side B solve a linear system
其具有系数矩阵它们
that has that coefficient matrix they
过去常常会在广场上出现新的a
used to would be in the squares a new a
新的测量或观察或数据
new measurement or observation or data
指出这些方块所以我的意思
point in these squares so what I mean
那么旧的我是什么意思呢
well what do I mean by this the old
问题是X等于B，我在想
problem was a X equal B and I'm thinking
我说的是最小方块
what I'm talking about least squares
在这里，我想象一个是矩形的
here I'm imagining that a is rectangular
-许多方程式教导a是一个高大的罪
- many equations taught a is a tall sin
矩阵只是我们一直在谈论的那种
matrix just the kind we've been talking
关于这个等式成为
about so that that equation becomes of
当然我们知道我们正常了
course we know we go to the normal
方程式a转置X是好的X是
equations a transpose a X the good X is
转置B
a transpose B
好的，现在我们得到一个新的测量所以a
okay now we get a new measurement so a
新测量如何新
new measurement how does the new
测量改变了这个问题
measurement change the problem so this
是之前的老问题
is the old problem before the
测量现在是一个新的
measurement comes in now a new
测量到了，这是另一个B.
measurement arrived so that's another B
aBn加1，我们得到另一个等式
a B n plus 1 and we get another equation
我们得到另一个正确的方程式
we get another equation right that's the
新的测量一个新点的
new measurement a new point to that the
直线试图贴近
straight line is trying to stay close to
所以我们称这个等式我不知道
so so we call this equation I don't know
我们应该怎么称呼它也许就是它
what we should call it maybe it's it'll
多一个排所以现在老现在是
be one more row so now old now it's
变得新鲜我有点兴奋
becoming new I'm sort of more excited
关于这个，然后改善
about this then and improving the
公式所以还是会这么好吗
formula so just keep going so okay
有我们的M测量和存在
there's our M measurements and being
大的a是高大的薄矩阵和
large a being the tall thin matrix and
现在我们要再给它一排
now we're gonna give it one more row
我们要让它甚至更高的发言权
we're gonna make it even taller say
也许V转置时间与X相同
maybe V transpose times the same X is
有些是新的或类似的东西，所以我们
some be new or something like that so we
所以再多一行了
so there's one more row one more
测量那么北方是什么
measurement so what's the north what
这是正常的等式
happens to the normal equation this is
这让你更有可能
this is makes it even more likely you
知道还有另外一点希望
know there's another point hoping the
直线将通过，但如果我们
straight line will go through but if we
再给它一点，甚至更少
give it one more point there's even less
直线前进的可能性
chance of a straight line going exactly
通过，但仍然是为什么这是我的
through but still so what why this is my
新矩阵所以我的新常态是什么
new matrix so what's my new normal
方程新的正规方程然后a
equation a new normal equation then a a
转置所以a有一个新的新的
transpose so a the a has got a new a new
row有一个新行，所以转置
row has got a new row so a transpose
将有一个我刚刚复制的新专栏
will have a new column I'm just copying
正常的等式，但我给它
the normal equation but I'm giving it
它的
its
新事物得到了一个新专栏，这是我的一个
new things got a new column this is my a
换了一排这是我最好的X帽子
with a new row this is my X hat my best
我最小的方块回答新的和a
my least squares answer new and a
transpose这是一个转置与
transpose is this a transpose with the
新的现在列时间b所以b和b新
new now column times b so b and b new
好吧相当好看这个
okay pretty okay with this to see that
这是新的正规方程式
this is the new normal equation i'm
使用新矩阵和新权利
using the new matrix and the new right
手边和另外一个数据点
hand side and just one more data point
已进入系统
has come into the into the system from
他们的传感器和关键点是什么
their sensor and what's the key point
这里的关键点是我不想
here key point is i don't want to
重新计算我不想乘以那个
recompute i don't want to multiply that
矩阵，我不想重新开始
matrix again i don't want to start over
我不想，我不想计算
I don't want to I don't want to compute
这是一个井II的转置时间
this a transpose times that a well I I
想要用我已经做过的事情
want to use what I've already done so
如果我成倍的是什么是什么
what is what is what is if I multiply
那两个在一起我实际上是什么
those two together what do I actually
得到这就是这是我正在添加一个新的
get so this is this is I'm adding a new
列在这里和新行在这里和我
column here and the new row here and I
告诉我你的想法是什么和答案
tell me what you think the answer is and
然后让我们看看为什么我问你
then let's just see why I'm asking you
什么那个矩阵是你怎么想的
what that matrix is what do you think
无论如何，让我知道如果
start me out to anyway they knew that if
我只是要求平凡
I just I'm just asking for ordinary
矩阵乘法很好我想我
matrix multiplication well I guess I'm
要求你按列行进行
asking you to do it columns times rows
因为那是1806五个专业
since that's what 1806 five specializes
因此，我认为我有那样的时间
in so I think I have that times that a
转置一个
transpose a
加上一个新列，一个nuRhoVV
plus one new column times one nu Rho VV
转置乘以这个Xhatnu
transpose is multiplying this X hat nu
我得到了正确的一面
and over on the right side I get
无论我有一个转置V老和
whatever I had the a transpose V old and
在V千伏新，但让我回来给
the V V new but let me come back to that
因为这真的告诉你为什么你
because that really shows you why you
必须理解矩阵乘法
must understand matrix multiplication
通常的行x列，但那
both the usual row x column but that
在这里也不会那么有吸引力
would not be so attractive here and also
列的时间为行的新方式
the new way as columns times rows
因为当我看到它作为列时间
because when I see it as columns times
行我看到我有相同的列
rows I see that I have the same columns
那里有相同的行，所以我就是我
and same rows there so I just what I
已经知道然后我有一个新的
already knew and then I have one new
列当然是一个新行
column times one new row of course
第n列加1，第n行
that's column n plus 1 and that's row n
再加1，他们给予等级1它是a
plus 1 and they give that rank 1 it's a
等级1在转置中改变它是a
rank 1 change in a transpose a it's a
等级1改变转置a这样
rank 1 change in a transpose a so this
就像最小正方形的一部分我
is like part of the of least squares I
意味着你可以看到一个相关性
mean you can see that the relevance in a
真正的问题，你可能有一个
real problem you you maybe have a
沿着你飞行的导弹送了一个
missile flying along you sent up a
您正在跟踪的卫星GPS卫星
satellite GPS satellite you're tracking
它只是在数据中输入更多数据
it more data comes in the data is just
跟踪器没有一个位置
one more position the tracker isn't
完美，所以我们在这里很适合我
perfect so we're gonna fit well here I'm
拟合直线也许我们就是
fitting a straight line maybe but we're
适合数据和唯一
fitting to the data and the the only
改变了左手的配偶
change in the mate in the left hand the
很大的问题，大部分的
big problem that the big part of the
计算是转置一个部分
computation is that a transpose a part
它只是按等级1或更改而改变
and it's just changed by rank 1 or by
如果我们有K个新数据点，则排名a
rank a if we had K new data points if we
有K个新的数据点然后这将是
had K new data points then this would be
一个雨洞
a rain cave
所以你看，然后我回到这里好吧
so you see then I go back here well okay
现在我正在扰乱a和我的转置
now I'm perturbing a transpose a and I
尚未给出那个公式
haven't given a formula for that one yet
到目前为止，我只是感到不安
I've only perturbed up to now the
身份，但你可以相信所有
identity but you can believe since all
谢尔曼，这些公式正在起作用
these formulas are working that Sherman
或莫里森或伍德伯里想出了
or Morrison or Woodbury came up with the
正确的置换扰动
correct permutation the perturbation for
一个转置，所以我很高兴
a transpose a so I'm sort of happy to
那个应用程序如此自然而然
that that application so natural came
如此简单，我就是那样的
out so simply well I'm on that sort of
你有没有听说过这个主题
subject have you ever heard of the
卡尔曼滤波器使牛仔过滤器
Kalman filter so the cowman filter
究竟是什么呢？
what's that about it's about exactly
这是关于它的动态平方
this it's about dynamically squares it's
关于最小二乘问题
about least squares problems in which
新数据即将出现，这是其中的一部分
new data is coming in that's a part a
卡尔曼滤波器或另一个词让我
Kalman filter or another word let me
在这里写几个字
just write a couple of words up here
这实际上是递归最小二乘法
this is really recursive least squares
递归最小二乘法我的意思
recursive least squares what I mean by
递归是新数据进来的
recursive is new data comes in it
改变答案，但不会改变
changes the answer but it doesn't change
我们的方法，然后卡尔曼滤波器
our method and then the Kalman filter is
如果，指导非常重要
a very very big deal in guidance if
如果你发送一枚导弹，你就是这样的
you're if you're sending up a missile a
卫星你跟踪它你做的只是
satellite you track it you do just just
我一直在这里讨论但是
what I've been discussing here but the
卡尔曼滤波器是它的更多
Kalman filter is it's it's got more
建立在这个可能性的可能性
possibilities built in than this one
这是最简单的更新
this is the simplest update possible and
它会打电话或进入这个类别
it would call or go in this category
库尔曼超越了标准更新
kulmann went beyond a standard update
如果我是的话，他是如何超越的呢？
how did he go beyond let's if I if I've
我应该使用卡尔曼滤波器这个词
used the words Kalman filter I should
告诉你卡尔曼是什么
tell you what what it is that Kalman
是什么，广场是什么
does and what is that the squares
问题就像一般的一部分
problem it's just like part of general
在我看来这些知识很好
knowledge that seems to me okay so what
是不是算多根哪些
is it counted more gen what are the
你看过主要的其他作品
additional pieces you've seen the main
这里有一个简单的递归的想法
idea here of getting a simple recursive
不需要重新计算的步骤
step that doesn't require recomputing
你之前和当然所做的一切
all that you did before and of course to
这反过来我会在那里申请
this inverse I'm going to apply there
谢尔曼莫里森将是这样的公式
shermann morrison would be formula so
我将使用之前的反转
I'll use the inverse that I had before
这将是一个排名第一
and this will be a rank one this is a
排名是我的一个扰动
rank one perturbation of that I'm
看着这里的转置
looking here at a transpose a over there
我看起来就像刚刚打电话一样
I was looking at just like just called
它或我甚至称它为身份
it a or I even called it the identity
矩阵但它是你拥有的任何矩阵
matrix but it's whatever matrix you have
这里有一级扰动和
here with a rank one perturbation and
整个事情必须倒置好
the whole thing has to be inverted okay
所以我要说的是什么
and so I was going to say what is
另外，你知道卡尔曼
additional just so you know about Kalman
过滤器，所以两件事是额外的
filters so two things are additional the
重点是卡尔曼滤波器
point the point is Kalman filters are
对于动态最小二乘，我会说
for dynamic least squares I would say
动态最小二乘等有
dynamic least squares and so there are
你没见过两种成分
two ingredients that you haven't seen
这里有一个成分是使用的想法
here one ingredient is the idea of using
协方差矩阵告诉你
the covariance matrix which tells you
错误如何相关
how errors are correlated
所以这将是加权最小二乘法
so that would be weighted least squares
或相关最小二乘这些
or correlated least squares these
正方形是这些方块让我公正
squares is so these squares let me just
提醒
remind
我可以在这里写这些广场
I can write it here so these square
标准标准意味着数据是
standard standard meaning that data is
不相关它都有相同的
not correlated it all has the same
方差这些是统计词
variance these are the statistics words
当我上次在这里时，我正在使用它
that I'm using when I last time in this
但是我会正确地谈论这个问题
but that I'll talk about properly so the
标准的是协变的
standard one is the covariant the
标准意味着协方差等于
standard means covariance equal the
您正在做的身份矩阵
identity matrix you're doing like
高斯正态概率但有
Gaussian normal probability but with
只是标准的高斯标准
just standard gaussians standard
高斯因此是其中的一个方面
Gaussian so that's one aspect which in
德雷珀实验室的工作让我们说
the work of the Draper lab let's say
他们必须认为他们得到了
they have to think okay they're getting
传感器不同类型的传感器与
sensors different kinds of sensors with
不同的准确度不同
different accuracies different
他们必须具备可靠性
reliability so they have they have to
考虑协方差矩阵
take account of the covariance matrix
那么另一点也是如此
then the other point is and also so that
是0.10.2是你的动态部分
was 0.1 0.2 is the dynamic part you're
那是一个状态方程式
the co there's a state equation that's
所以我真的处于控制的边缘
so I'm really into the edge of control
理论所以让我用一些话来说
theory so let me just use some words
在这里，你已经看到你是否如此控制
here that you've seen if you so control
理论有一个状态方程是什么
theory has a state equation what's
在美学上这是什么状态
aesthetically what is the state this is
在我的例子中，位置是
the position in my example is the
卫星的位置
position of the satellite
所以我们正在寻找一个令人高兴的解决方案
so are we looking for a fix a delight
当然不是卫星正在移动
certainly not the satellite is moving so
状态方程告诉我多少
the state equation tells me how much the
卫星它的牛顿定律告诉我
satellite it's Newton's law tells me
卫星应该在哪里
where the satellite should be where am I
看着
looking
然后最小二乘告诉我他
and then the least-squares tells me he
说看看那种中位数
says look around that sort of median
对于实际位置立场
position for the actual position that
这些数据只是给予了
that the data is giving so just just to
说让我让我总结这个
say let me let me summarize this the
卡尔曼滤波器是一个显着的
Kalman filter is a significantly
递归方格的改进版本
improved version of recursively squares
那是递归的新方格
that's recursively squares new
测量是变化的事情但是
measurement comes in changes things but
留下很大一部分，你做的
leaves a big part unchanged and you make
你发现新发现的新东西
the you find the new you find that new
用卡尔曼滤波器退出你有一个
exit with a Kalman filter you there's a
这里中间的协方差矩阵
covariance matrix in the middle here
这就是协方差矩阵的地方
that's where covariance matrices go
这是矩阵协方差或逆矩阵
that's matrix covariance or inverse
协方差时间以及为什么不这样做
covariance times that and well why don't
我们看到右边的协方差
we see see the covariances at the right
时间好吧所以也许我的那些会议纪要
time okay so maybe my those minutes that
我已经占据了真正要得到的
I've occupied were just to really to get
你最简单的听到这个名字
you to hear that name for the simplest
更新和凯尔曼的名字更多
update and kellman's name for a more
一般更新没事
general update okay done
好吧哦，这也是要做的
okay oh that was this is also to be done
你在哪里知道顶部
where's ya know up top
我似乎在这里的应用程序
I seem to be into the applications here
我答应如何发现这个公式
I promised how to discover the formula
也许我永远都不会知道，因为我
maybe I'll never know okay because I'm
真的更感兴趣的是它的好处
really more interested in what's it good
对于
for
好的，那么使用第一名是好的
okay so what's it good use number one
现在我正在备份轻松简单
now I'm backing up to the easy easy
问题假设II已经或者然后让
question suppose I I had or and then let
我甚至做了一些矩阵来改变
me even make some matrix to change the
矩阵到这里使它更现实
matrix to a here makes it more realistic
还好还好我要去的副本，在这里充分
okay okay I'm gonna copy that here fully
在发现公式的那一刻
on discovering the formula the moment
我们只是用它好了，所以我想，
let's just use it okay so I suppose that
一个U就是它的盐现在好了，现在盐了
a U is be its salt okay now now salt a
加-好吧让我排名第一
plus - all right let me do the rank one
a-UV转置B这是什么X.
a - UV transpose B what's X this is the
我真的很想问题
problem that I really would like to
解决，让我确定我这样做
solve let me just be sure I'm doing this
对
right
是的是的还好没事想你我
yep okay yep all right suppose I you
知道它有点类似于什么
know it's a little it's similar to what
我们在凯勒曼的情况下
we had in the Kellerman situation
假设我现在解决了一个问题
suppose I've solved one problem but now
我把第一级扰乱了矩阵，所以我
I perturb the matrix by rank one so I
有一个新的问题，新的答案，
have a new problem with a new answer and
我想快点得到答案，是的
I want to get that answer quickly yeah
哦，不，谢谢
oh no thank you
非常感谢，让我们称呼这个人
thank you very much let's call this guy
Z好的没关系，这太好了
Z okay okay so that's great
所以这就是我解决的问题
so so that's that's what I've solved for
换句话说，我发现了一个逆
W in other words I have found a inverse
B和我想找到这个问题的答案
B and I want to find the answer to that
新问题
new question
所以我扰乱矩阵就是这样
so I perturb the matrix it's it's the
线性系统中的系数矩阵
coefficient matrix in a linear system
而我只是想解决那个线性问题
and I just want to solve that linear
系统还好，如果我不知道的话
system okay now so if I didn't know
关于这些公式我会做什么的
anything about these formulas I would
这里有一个新矩阵我必须这样做
have a new matrix here I'd have to it
需要n个立方体步骤才能完成
would take n cube steps to do
消除并得到新的答案
elimination and and get the new answer
但重点是使用旧的答案
but the point is to use the old answer
重点是使用旧的答案和
the point is to use the old answer and
现在让我说一下这是什么和
now let me just say what this is and
这是本节中的问题三，但是
it's problem three in this section but
好的
so okay
换句话说，我们知道我们已经知道了
so in other words we know about a we've
解决了那个我要做的事情
solved that one so what I'm gonna do
而不是解决一个全新的问题
instead of solving a whole new problem
我会这么快就有了这个主意
I'm gonna so quickly it's the idea and
这就是我要解决的想法
here's the idea I'm gonna I've solved
那一个，我要解决一秒钟
that one and I'm gonna solve a second
问题也解决了同样的问题
problem also solve a with the same
矩阵a呐喊一次我应该怎样
matrix a whoops a times what shall I
打电话给未知
call the unknown
还有的电子ü所以这是我的问题，我知道
there's e u so this is my problem I know
U和V转置，但我没有
the U and the V transpose but I don't
真想找到这个的倒数
really want to find the inverse of this
从头开始的矩阵所以这个想法就是这样
matrix from scratch so the idea is that
如果我合适地结合起来
if I combine suitably combine the
原始问题的解决方案
solutions to the original problem the
原始解决方案W和解决方案
original solution W and the solution to
这个问题跟你那里的新人有关
this problem with the new guy you there
不论如何，到结合W和
that somehow by combining the W and the
Z我会得到这个答案X的
Z I'm gonna get this answer X that's
通过弄清楚W，我就是那样的
where I'm that's um by by figuring out W
和Z所以你看到我做了什么我已经
and Z so do you see what I've done I've
解决了我已解决的矩阵问题
solved the with the matrix a I've solved
两个问题确实需要两倍
two problems does that take twice as
如果我有相同的矩阵a
long if I if I have the same matrix a
但不同的右手边b如果我
but different right hand sides b if i
把它变成了鲁的所有艰苦工作
factor it a into Lu all the hard work is
虽然全部在左侧完成
done there on the left side although all
这项工作是在找到卢然后完成的
the work is done in finding Lu and then
我只是替代找到了
I just back substitute to find the
第二种解决方案这是如此根本
second solution this is so fundamental
我强调的是，如果你有
that I'm emphasizing it that if you have
你没有多个右手边
multiple right-hand sides you don't
每次都回去工作
every time go back and and work on the
左侧与左侧相同
left side the left side with the same
矩阵
matrix a
只是会做同样的事情
just would do the same stuff the same
罗斯维尔和枢轴以及所有这些东西
Roseville and pivots and all that stuff
会发生，因为它和你一样
will happen because it's the same a you
只是附上你真的只是坚持一个
just attach you really just stick a
第二列确实是快速的方法
second column really the the fast way to
做到这两个解决方案来了
do it is a w-z the two solutions come
从B和你我刚才把它
from the B and the you I've just put the
两个问题，共同强调，
two problems together to emphasize that
矩阵A是它的这个相同
the matrix a is the same it's the this
是大多数工作的地方，但它
is where most of the work goes but it
只有这一点才会到那里
only goes there once that's the point
好的
okay
最后我应该记笔记
then finally I'm supposed to the notes
应该告诉我如何结合
are supposed to tell me how to combine
两个答案W和Z得到了
the two answers W and Z to get the
回答X所以让我写下来
answer X so let me write that down
这将是使用号码
and that will be that will be use number
谢尔曼·莫里森之一
one of the of the shermann morrison
伍德伯里公式好，所以我正在计划
Woodberry formula okay so i'm planning
根据这个把它写下来
to just write it down according to this
第二步是我们想要的答案
step two is the answer we want here
写X所以我没有用过相同的
written X so I haven't used the same
笔记中的字母是原件
letters as in the notes is the original
好，然后改变，因为我
W good and then a change because I've
改变了问题所以我要去
changed the problem so I'm going to
改变答案，但事情是
change the answer but the thing is to
得到这个答案就是我必须的
get this answer it's just I have to
在任何地方除以那个决定因素
divide by that determinant wherever it
虽然哦，是的，我很抱歉，我正在使用
was though oh yeah I'm sorry I'm using
这里的一个，我还没有给你的
the a here and I haven't given you the
公式为使将不得不等待，所以
formula for a so that'll have to wait so
它就是这样，我会在这里确定
it's just so I'll put determinate here
和shermann莫里森会想通
and shermann morrison would be figured
那个，然后哦，对不起，我们知道
that out and then oh I'm sorry we know
那是什么我们想要一个减去V
what that is we want one minus V
转置Z所以它是这里的V之一
transpose Z so it's the V from here one
减去V转置，它就是那里的Z.
minus V transpose and it's the Z there
噢，好的，所以我会得到一个
oh yeah okay good so so I'm gonna get a
改变解W的公式
formula that that changes the solution W
通过我们认识到的一个术语来临
by a term that we recognize is coming
来自谢尔曼莫里森伍德伯里和那
from shermann morrison Woodbury and that
分子中的项是Z的倍数
term in the numerator is a multiple of Z
X所以我使用W是W倍X所以V
X so I'm using W yes W times X so the V
在这里我只是使用V是一样的
here I'm just using the V is the same
事情那么好我认为那是我认为的上帝
thing so okay I think that's God I think
这很好，所以重点是2倍
that's good so again the point was 2x
不会出现在这里，因为它是什么
doesn't appear here because it's what
我之后是使用W和Z的
I'm after is to use the W and the Z the
W和Z和我当然必须使用
W and the Z and I have to use of course
V和我必须使用U和那个
the V and I have to use the U and that
在这里使用所以必须的一切
got used here so everything that had to
使用得到了，这就是答案
be used got used and that was the answer
所以这是基本用途，如果我是，如果我
so that's the basic use is if I'm if I
扰动问题的左手
perturbed the problem the the left hand
那边解决方案的变化是什么
side what's the change in the solution
在这里与这些广场
over here with these squares
这是我扰乱左手的一样
it was the same I perturb the left hand
侧
side
但因为那里有正方形
but because it was these squares there
是一个转置辅助处理如此
was an a transpose aid to deal with so
这就像一个级别更难
this was like one level more difficult
因为它涉及转置王牌和
because it involved a transpose ace and
这里只是直白啊好了，
here was just straightforward eh okay so
是的，谢谢我可能会这样做
yes thanks I could probably do this
其他方式是啊是啊是的我希望你
other ways yeah yeah yeah I hope you
希望你能跟进这一点，把它写
hope you follow up on that and write it
是的，是的，所以也许我做了什么
down yeah yeah so maybe what I've done
是我今天的目标首先是
is what my goal was for today first to
显示逆的公式
show you the formula for the inverse
第二，认识到它有
second to recognize that it has
排名K的有趣重要性
interesting importance that a rank K
矩阵的变化带来了等级a
change in the matrix brings a rank a
我们可以改变倒数
change in the inverse and that we can
该公式表示将N反转为n
the formula says to invert an N by n
你可以通过矩阵切换和反转K.
matrix you can switch and invert a K by
K矩阵，然后我谈到了一对
K matrix and then I spoke about a couple
应用程序所以我唯一的事情
of the applications so the only thing I
没做的就是给你全力
have not done is to give you the full
讲道莫里森伍德伯里公式
sermon Morrison Woodberry formula the
一个人就是一个人
one with an a the one that's up on the
我可以最终做到这一点
right can I do that finally you could
可能猜猜它会是什么
probably guess what it's going to be
哪里还有一个还好
where's there's gotta be one more okay
所以我只听到谢尔曼马辛伍德伯里
so I I just hear Sherman Marcin Woodbury
什么是完整的东西呢
and what's the complete thing it's a
减去UV转置，所以这是n
minus UV transpose inverse so this is n
由N和它现在是一个A而不是一个
by N and it's an A now instead of an
身份矩阵就是区别
identity matrix that's the difference
这是由KKbyn所以它的等级
and this is n by K K by n so it's rank
洞穴扰动和开始我出去
Cave perturbation and start me out on
在公式上什么是第一个
the on the formula what's the first
我必须写一个反转所以我
thing I have to write a inverse so I
从反向开始，我减去
start with a inverse and I subtract
什么东西，它会是一个副本
something and it's gonna be a copy of
这个除了好吧也许它只是可能
this except well maybe it's just maybe
它只是一个完美的副本也许我只是
it's just a perfect copy maybe I just
我需要你从左边开始
need to you I'm going from that left
现在我登上了洞穴，我放在那里
board now I cave where do I put in there
我要去要确定一下所以我们
I am gonna have to look ok so we're
现在写下完整的公式
writing down now the formula the full
比例没关系
scale okay
哦，没事在这里是有一个一个
oh all right here it is there's an a
反过来你现在来了整个
inverse you now comes the in that whole
倒过来，你会期待我
thing inverted that you'll expect I
减去V转置你所有的逆
minus V transpose a inverse you all
逆，然后还有另外两个
inverse and then there's another two
件V转置反转所以我没有
pieces V transpose a inverse so I didn't
展望未来，将它全部放在一条线上，但是
look ahead to get it all on one line but
你明白这是什么哦那是
do you see what this is there oh that's
可能就是那个是的
probably is that yeah that's the
身份正确，因为我们已经拥有
identity right right because we've got
足够的倒数我相信是的
enough a inverses I believe that's the
生命的最后终极公式在这里，
final ultimate formula of life here that
我们用等级K改变了它
we've changed it by rank K
这是原始的逆和
here's the original inverse and
大概这是K级改变是的
presumably this is a rank K change yeah
那将是一个变化和排名
that's a that'll be a rank a change and
它只需要我们来计算它
and it only requires us to compute that
反转那里的电缆是K的
inverse where that's cable that's a K by
K矩阵对，谢谢你允许
K matrix right thank you for allowing
这小时50分钟的公式如此
this hour 50 minutes of formulas so
这真的是什么来如此
that's really what what that comes to so
所以这是第四节中的第一节
so that's section four point one of the
注意到一些应用程序，我们会
notes with some applications and we will
move on to other circumstances of low
转移到低其他情况
排名好谢谢
rank good thank you